y'all want some more cardio we're all
familiar with the NordicTrack treadmills
exercise bikes and rowers but you can't
forget about the free stride I've been
using the fs10i for a while now and
trust me there's a lot to talk about so
let's get to work
what's up everybody it's Jake back in
the barbing garage gym and for today's
video I have the NordicTrack fs10i
freestride N4 review in this video I'm
gonna go over all the details from the
price the features some pros and cons
most importantly who should or maybe
should not purchase one of these now
before I start doing all that we've
reviewed a lot of ellipticals on
barbin.com so if you want to browse our
best list all you got to do is search
barvin best ellipticals our list is
going to pull up for you and you can
find out for yourself which ones that we
like the best
[Music]
foreign
stride first of all I love how
NordicTrack integrates iFit within all
of their cardio equipment it's gonna be
really nice you know you have a lot of
trainer-led workouts there's over 16 000
to be exact with iFit so you're never
going to get bored you're never going to
run out of possibilities in terms of
your workouts you have a 10 inch
touchscreen display you have 24 levels
of resistance 10 degrees of incline you
have a 32 inch adjustable stride length
and I say adjustable because this is
technically a three in one it's going to
operate and act as a StairMaster an
elliptical and even a treadmill all
based off of your specific stride and
it's going to change in the matter of
seconds it might be a little bit weird
to get used to it first but overall it's
a pretty smooth process you have a
built-in fan and a water bottle holder
there's Bluetooth capabilities for your
headphones or a heart rate monitor
there's manual adjustments you can make
for your resistance and your incline
there's even popular music loaded onto
the monitor as well
now let's talk about a couple issues
that I noticed that you might also
notice let's talk about the overall size
of the freeze stride first as you can
see it's pretty big it's also pretty
tall so you know finding the right space
in your home is going to be tough for
some people especially because you do
have that 32 inch stride length so you
know these legs feet whatever you want
to call them they're going to stick out
pretty far and it might bump into your
wall or something so definitely just
keep that in mind it's also pretty
expensive it's priced right around two
grand which you know that might be a bit
of a turn off for some people but you
know it's a luxury item you kind of got
to pay that luxury price tag after your
first month of iFit that's free you're
gonna have to come up with some type of
plan either you pay monthly yearly
there's three different yearly plans you
can choose from so you know it's going
to add on to an already expensive
product got to have really good Wi-Fi
you know I'm in a garage we all know
this by now and I'm not next to my Wi-Fi
router but you know there's still some
times where the Wi-Fi doesn't want to
connect and it can be a bit of a
headache and also you know it might take
a while to buffer some of the workouts
but you know there's 16 000 workouts
loaded onto this monitor so you know a
little bit of give and take right there
it's also you know heavy it weighs 280
pounds so you know yes it comes in handy
that you have wheels and a handle to
make it portable but it's definitely not
easy to move it around and these legs
right here you can't lock them into
place that would be nice because you
know there's sometimes I'm moving it it
kind of bumps me it doesn't hurt but you
know it can kind of be annoying at times
[Music]
okay so in terms of pricing you know
once again the freeze stride from
NordicTrack is available for right
around two thousand dollars and that's
kind of pricey but my personal opinion
you know once you really factor in all
the awesome features with this product
right here I think it's worth the money
you know it's technically a three in one
StairMaster elliptical and a treadmill
with the way you can move the legs and
kind of adjust your stride a little bit
so you're not really you know limited to
what you can do and plus there's a bunch
of classes available at your disposal
right at your fingertips so if you're
somebody who thrives off that you know
you want a personal trainer type
experience with your workouts this is
one of the best options available on the
market but let's say you know you don't
care about streaming your workouts you
don't care about the touchscreen monitor
all of that you know fancy stuff you can
definitely save you know a good amount
of money by going down a cheaper route
you can also Finance this purchase if
you want to it's definitely going to
depend off of your original pricing you
know so if you want an extra extended
warranty if you want one of the three
different options in terms of the iFit
membership that's all going to change
the overall price tag cool thing is
though NordicTrack does a really good
job of breaking down your monthly
payments and they also give you a couple
different payment plans to choose from
all right so let's talk about the
available classes and the iFit companion
app now it's definitely not a secret at
this point that there's a lot of classes
for you to choose from on your free
stride there's 16 000 classes available
through iFit but NordicTrack also went
ahead and preloaded 35 workouts onto
this product right here which is really
nice you know you don't have to you know
sign up for iFit if you don't want to
but I personally think that's going to
be worth the money especially if you
plan on using it you know pretty
frequently you can join a studio class
where you get that you know Studio feel
you can travel the world with a personal
trainer you can pick the city of your
choice and create your own workout you
can simply you know do a manual workout
and adjust your resistance incline all
it by yourself but that's not all I mean
you can bust out some dumbbells and join
a strength training class or maybe even
just you know work on your flexibility
and join a stretching class point is
there's a lot right there at your
fingertips that you can choose from but
you can also stream all those other
classes that don't require the free
stride directly from your phone so on
top of streaming those classes from the
iFit companion app that app is also a
really great tool in terms of tracking
your stats your activity in the past
week month year to date you can always
check out your progression and just you
know kind of see your overall Fitness
level from that you can also click on
the calendar tab it's going to show you
your recently completed workouts you've
done you can go to the trophies Tab and
see you know the challenges you've
completed it's also going to show your
current progress on any challenge you're
trying to complete and if you haven't
done any or maybe you're just looking
for a new one you can click on Discover
challenges right there as well and it's
going to just show you that full list of
available challenges those are also
being added all the time so that's
really cool too
okay so clearly there's a lot of
Technology with the free stride but
let's kind of break that down a little
bit so all of nordictrack's equipment
operates with Android os9 technology so
you know pretty up to date it's really
modern it's going to be relatively quick
in terms of the interface and just kind
of operating through the menus you have
that 10 inch touchscreen monitor it does
tilt a little bit so you can kind of
accommodate for your height a little bit
as well there are manual adjustments
that are on either side of the monitor
as well as on either side of the fan as
well so that's really nice you have it
at your disposal but you know if you're
doing a trainer lead workout you don't
even have to really worry about that at
all because it's going to automatically
adjust on its own I also really like how
NordicTrack integrated Google Maps with
their cardio equipment as well that way
you can pick you know San Francisco New
York you know Hawaii you know any City
Hawaii you can pick anywhere in the
world literally and you can come up with
your own workout and kind of map out the
city and do that all on your own it's
all going to adapt to the layout of the
city which is you know just a really
cool thing you do have Bluetooth
capabilities this is going to be really
nice for anybody who wants to stream
their workouts through their headphones
or you know if you want to really track
your heart rate because there's not any
heart rate sensors built into the
handles so it's definitely going to be
something you want to you know check out
there's also a lot of popular music
loaded onto the monitor as well which is
really cool you know you're not stuck
with some boring random instrumental you
have you know up-to-date music there's
classic rock there's a bunch of
different options to choose from as well
so that's also really nice and it's also
a relatively quiet machine so you know
it's obviously going to make a little
bit of noise as it inclines and then you
kind of levels back out it doesn't
decline but it technically does decline
from that highest incline position and
that's honestly a relatively quiet
experience
foreign
okay so let's talk about the build now
and some of the features with the
NordicTrack freeze stride it's got a
steel framework there is some plastic
mixed in really the only thing that I've
noticed that might be a cause for
concern for me specifically right now is
this plastic right here underneath this
pedal doesn't really want to stay
together and I think it's going to be
okay but it's definitely something worth
mentioning this is about 74 inches tall
about 58 and a half inches long or so
and about 30 inches wide it weighs a
hefty 284 pounds so thankfully there is
a handle and a set of wheels it's gonna
make it pretty easy to move it around
your personal space it has a 375 pound
weight limit which is a really solid
number and I really love the fact that
NordicTrack includes a 10-year warranty
on the framework of their equipment you
have a 10 inch touchscreen monitor
that's honestly pretty easy to use it's
a nice Crystal Clear HD picture you know
just so long as you have a pretty strong
Wi-Fi connection you have a 10 inch
touchscreen monitor it's really easy to
use it has a nice HD picture you know
just so long as you have a strong Wi-Fi
connection there's automatic adjustments
to your resistance and your incline
which is really cool but you also have
multiple locations for manual
adjustments as well they're on either
side of the monitor as well as on either
side of the built-in fan the fan also
has adjustments as well you can also
adjust the volume there's a lot of
adjustments here clearly that you can
make to this machine but also like how
you can adjust the stride length in a
matter of seconds as well it's going to
respond to how you're moving so
technically get that feeling of an
elliptical a StairMaster I guess you
could say and even a treadmill
all-in-one which is pretty sweet
all right so let's go ahead and walk you
guys around the free straw and also kind
of demonstrate how it kind of operates
so first of all nice steel framework
right there yeah there's some plastic
built in but you know that's that's the
normal right with cardio equipment so it
seems really stable and other than that
one issue underneath my pedal it seems
really durable as well now when it comes
to the actual interface kind of how
everything operates it's a pretty simple
process you know here you have your
touch screen monitor you can navigate
through the menu you can find all your
different workouts I mean as you can see
I mean it's you can sit here and scroll
for days and there's different
categories hiking running walking
beginner walk run I mean there's so many
different things you can choose from you
can go to calendar and find your
previous workouts that you've done
does pop-up go away really fast
and then you can go to create and kind
of go to any city in the world and
create your own I like how every single
time you click on create it pops up with
a brand new city so it's almost like
you're getting suggestions like right
now just clicked on it and it said
Central Park New York so that's really
cool next time I do it it might say you
know somewhere in California wherever
it's it's pretty cool you go to browse
and you can simply just you know browse
all the available workouts and then you
have your trophy case down there at the
bottom as well and that's going to take
you to any challenges you've completed
and then also there's going to be a
discover challenges right here but you
can click on and it kind of takes you to
all the available challenges that are
out there you do have your manual
adjustments for your incline and your
resistance on either side of the monitor
right here but you also have them on
either side of the fan as well and
that's that's pretty cool you know these
are going to go up in 0.1 increments
down here and as you can see these are
going to go directly you know in
correspondence to the number that is you
know displayed on either side of that
monitor you also have two two inch
speakers right here which you know
sounds really nice but also like how
this kind of acts like a tray right here
underneath the monitor so you know let's
say you've got you know an iPad a tablet
whatever you want to stream your
favorite show you can definitely do that
just set it right there and you're good
to go you also have your fan adjustments
and speed adjustments right there I like
the handles they give you a nice little
grip you know whenever you're working
out but it would be cool if they did
have a heart rate sensor right there so
you didn't have to go and buy a heart
rate monitor so you know if you really
want to track your heart rate
variability you're going to have to get
one of those now
really cool thing here that's what I
think is makes this product super unique
is how these pedals are going to adjust
to how you move so yeah I'm not in a
class right now but here I'll show you
so you can kind of act like kind of acts
like a StairMaster you can just step up
and down
and it also is going to immediately
adjust to the way you're moving so now
it's kind of like an elliptical and then
you can adjust it again and it's kind of
like you're running on a treadmill so
that's honestly just really cool in my
opinion all right so we're in here right
now and let me go and end that warm up
slide this back over so all of your
metrics are going to be right here so
your speed estimated calories burned
that's obviously going to be precise if
you have a heart rate monitor time
elapsed your resistance and that's just
a really cool tool you know it's going
to show you everything it's going to be
the same case you know as you're in one
of those trainer lead workouts and
you're always going to know you know
exactly what you're working with
[Applause]
okay so who should purchase the
NordicTrack freeze stride well if you
are in fact looking for a way to get
some low impact cardio into your workout
routine I think this is one of the
better options out there you know
there's a lot of trainer-led classes
right at your fingertips also you know
since it does have that adjustable
stride length I think that's you know a
really nice thing as well it's really
unique technically a three in one
product with an elliptical StairMaster
and a treadmill you tie in all those
luxury features for a price tag that's
right around two thousand dollars I
think it's money well spent
[Music]
now when it comes to those who might not
want to purchase the freeze stride it
comes down to three different things
money first and foremost yes I know I
just said that the price seems justified
in my opinion and that's still true but
you know it also is true two thousand
dollars is still two thousand dollars
and if you can't stomach spending that
much money on a piece of cardio
equipment I suggest looking for
something cheaper also you know it's
kind of large right especially tall so
finding the right space for some people
was you know gonna be a bit of a hassle
if you don't have the available space
well then you don't really need to
purchase this product right here and
lastly is just your interest level maybe
even lack of interest level and
streaming workouts you don't care about
doing that then I suggest going and
finding a cheaper and more basic piece
of equipment well that's a wrap on
today's review over the NordicTrack
fs10i free stride if you are on the
market for a high-tech piece of cardio
equipment I definitely think you found
your match just be prepared to drop two
grand on it and be sure to clear the way
in your home or else you won't have
enough space for it thanks for watching
y'all I hope this video was really
helpful that I was able to tell you
exactly what to expect with this product
right here as always keep your eyes
peeled for my next video but for now you
should head over to barbin.com to read
more about this product all you gotta do
is search bar Bend NordicTrack fs10i
freestride trainer review and you can
find all the details I discussed here
today I'll catch y'all next time
[Music]